hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our test
automation obstacles topic with trien
tosa let's look at our next obstacle
which is called scroll into view now
here the obstacle seems it's pretty
simple that you need to enter tosa into
text box but the catch here is the text
will disappear once the text box is out
of the visible area so here if you look
here uh I cannot enter the text directly
because currently this particular text
box is not in view and something is
blocking the UI now if I scroll this to
the bottom then the text box is going to
come into the view and then I I can
enter some text here okay and then I can
click on submit to complete this
obstacle so this is what we need to do
in tosa so let's see how we can perform
this particular
automation so coming back to tosa uh
first of all we are going to scan this
particular module so I'm going to scan
the application
here and now we are going going to add
uh the particular text field and also we
are going to uh select the submit button
so these are the two objects which we
want to add and as you can see the text
field uh is uh embedded inside iframe
and then there is an HTML document
inside which there is the text field
okay so these are the two controls which
we need currently so I'm going to save
and I'm going to to also rename this
obstacle before I close it so I'm going
to rename this module here then I'm
going to save and I'm going to
close now the next thing which uh we
have to do is we need to add some more
Properties or parameters into this
particular text field because as you
know we need to scroll in order to get
this particular field into the view okay
and for this uh we can use something
called the steering parameter in tosa
okay so when you right click on this
particular field then uh you can add a
steering parameter okay so that is an
option to create steering parameter so
click on that and we are going to rename
this steering parameter property to
scrolling
Behavior
okay so in this scrolling Behavior
steering parameter we have got four
different values uh which is top bottom
center and none so what it does is it
allows you to Define where the control
should be positioned on the screen and
for this it can scroll uh to top to
bottom or to Center okay so what we are
going to do uh we are going to mention
the value here as top so that this
particular uh scrolling Behavior helps
us to bring this particular uh control
uh to the right position on the screen
okay once you do that then uh it's
becomes very simple we just uh need to
add the test case here so we are going
here and we are adding a new test
case Okay and then uh I'm going to add
the module right
here and then uh we just need to enter
the text here so I'm going to enter tosa
here and then um this is the first step
the next step is to click on submit so
I'm going to use another test step for
that okay and I'm going to perform the
click operation here using X now uh also
what we can do is we can rename the
steps so here I will say enter
text and here I will say click
submit
okay so this is all we have to do in
this particular obstacle uh we can set
the work state to complete it and then
uh we can try and run this particular
test case now okay so let's go ahead and
run this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see uh
the scrolling Behavior helped us to
bring that control into the particular
position so that it is visible and then
uh it is in View and then we can type
the text into that particular text
box so similarly you can use different
steering parameters to change the
behavior of your particular controls uh
in your application tosa provides a
number of different steering parameters
which can be
used that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video